Jackson Ogles

Summary of Qualifications

Over 5 years of professional information technology experience. Significant experience in **React**, **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **Vue**, **Node**, **PostgreSQL** and more.

Technical Skills

Technologies/Tools: JavaScript, React, Vue, NodeJS, GraphQL, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Styled

Components, TailwindCSS, Git Version Control, RESTful APIs

Professional Experience

Web Developer, HQ Digital Product Agency React, Node, PostgreSQL

November 2024 - Present

- Built responsive and dynamic UIs using React, Styled Components, and JavaScript, integrating tools like TinyMCE and Pintura Editor.
- Developed and optimized RESTful APIs with Node.js, leveraging Prisma for efficient database management with PostgreSQL.
- Ensured seamless front-end and back-end integration, focusing on performance, security, and scalability.

Software Engineer I, Nu Skin Enterprises *Vue, jQuery, NodeJS*

April 2022 – December 2023

- Worked on an agile team with a Scrum Master, Product Owner, UX Designer, QA Engineer, Tech Lead Engineer, and myself.
- Built out the catalog product detail page for Bundled Products UI with Vue. Learned Vue on the job. This task required intensive state management between components within the Nuxt Vue App, as well as good styling and performance.
- See one of the bundles here for example: https://www.nuskin.com/us/en/search/bundle.
- Updated dependencies (specifically jQuery) as part of a security compliance effort in all of the product domain repositories on GitLab.
- Tested UI and API interaction within Vue and NodeJS API. Completed duties in given time frames, and worked with the team to establish those timelines and duties.

Web Developer, HQ Digital Product Agency

August 2020 – April 2022

JavaScript, React, SEO, JAMstack

- Ensured statically generated websites were performant and sometimes dynamic with React.
- Improved SEO and accessibility for multiple projects.
- Wrote documentation for codebases in Markdown and via inline comments when appropriate.
 Wrote detailed commit messages and wrote good Merge Request submissions so feature introductions were easy to review.

Team Lead, Lambda School (Bloomtech)

January 2019 - March 2019

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Node, Data Structures, Algorithms

 Mentored a group of nine students as they practiced and learned CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React, Node, and Data Structures and Algorithms. Facilitated standup each day and worked directly with instructors and students to improve probability of successful learning.

Web Developer, Freelance

Vue, React, HTML, CSS

- Developed and maintained the Lindy's Local Pest Control website using React and LESS for a responsive and maintainable UI. <u>Visit site</u>.
- Contracted with CleanSmarts to assist in transitioning their front end to Vue, including implementing a Vue-based navigation component with a chat widget, legal page links, and an animated sidebar expansion effect. Visit site.
- Enhanced the front-end of the online RPG *Obsidian Tears* by implementing React with Tailwind CSS for a sleek and responsive UI. <u>Visit site</u>.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science, *Psychology*

Brigham Young University